Guide to the Roy Gill Papers on the Columbia Basin Irrigation League 1920-1942
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Roy Gill Papers on the Columbia Basin Irrigation League
1920-1942
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 247
Gill, Roy Roland, 1876-
0.75 Linear feet of shelf space 2 boxes
This collection of Roy Roland Gill's papers focuses on his activities as an officer of the Columbia Basin Irrigation League.
Roy Roland Gill of Spokane, WA, was Executive Chairman and Secretary of the Columbia Basin Irrigation League during the 1920s. He also served as the president of the Spokane Chamber of Commerce (1922-1923). During his years in Spokane, Gill worked as vice president and general manager of the Holley-Mason Hardware Company.
This collection of Roy Roland Gill's papers focuses on his activities as an officer of the Columbia Basin Irrigation League. The League was an advocacy and lobbying group for development of Inland Northwest water resources for irrigation and hydroelectric power production. The collection consists of correspondence, reports, minutes, publications, speeches, financial records, legislation, clippings and photographs related to the League's promotional activities. Gill's correspondence makes up most of the collection. He received letters and telegrams from a wide range of correspondents, many of them federal officials, corporate executives, and prominent regional businessmen, offering information, strategy suggestions, assessment of progress, and analysis of developments. Some noteworthy correspondents are Herbert Hoover, Hervey Lindley, Elwood Mead, Hubert Work, Mark E. Reed, Miles Poindexter, and William Borah.
The collection is arranged in a single series.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Roy Gill donated this collection to the Washington State University Libraries (date unknown).
Osmar Lysander Waller Papers, 1897-1935 (Cage 222)
Columbia Basin Irrigation League Papers, 1923-1932 (Cage 5031)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Gill, Roy Roland, 1876- -- Correspondence; Lindley, Hervey -- Correspondence; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964 -- Correspondence; Mead, Elwood, 1858-1936 -- Correspondence
Columbia Basin Irrigation League -- Records and correspondence; Columbia Basin Project (U.S.)
Dams -- Washington (State); Pressure groups -- Washington (State); Barrages
Washington (State); Water and Water Rights
- Correspondence: 1921-1927 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Correspondence: 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Correspondence: 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: 1932-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
- Draft of Senate Bill (S. 2860), A bill to provide for the construction, operation, and maintenance of the Columbia Basin project in Washington, and for other purposes. 72nd Congress, 1st Session, 1932. Printed, manuscript, and typescript versions, some heavily annotated. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Reports (about the Columbia Basin Project) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Publications and clippings (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
- Financial statements, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Minutes and conference proceedings, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Speeches (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Photograph of Miss Alice Garry, Princess America I, and Herbert Hoover, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 15)